Chris Cummings

Software Developer

chris@chriscummings.net United States, SC (Eastern TZ)

Summary

Languages: Python (16 yrs), JavaScript (17 yrs), CSS & HTML (17 yrs),

Ruby (5 yrs), **PHP, C, Rust** (1 yrs)

Frameworks: Flask, Django, Ruby-on-Rails, Bootstrap, React, Dojo

Misc: Docker, Git, Node.js, Redis, PostgreSQL, MySQL, GIS

Experience

Developer/Owner - Dingo Ranch Labs, LLC (2022 - Present)

- Developed research analyst tools for InkStickMedia.com in Python to crawl financial and government websites & APIs to surface data and patterns of interest to "watchdog" groups.
- Led and launched a diverse list of small client projects. (API Integrations, Web Scraping, CRUD, Status/Control Panels, CMS Admin, GIS & Software Consulting)

Developer - Bell, Carrington, Price & Gregg (2021 - 2022)

- Developed internal product to automate identifying property parcels to be impacted by future eminent domain construction projects and fetch associated property tax records. (Django, JavaScript, ESRI ArcGIS Online)
- Created scripts and web services to automate the processing of raw Dept. of Transportation .PDF engineering drawings and GIS data into useful georeferenced vector map data. (QGIS, Python)

Software Engineer - Dominion Energy (Power & Gas) (2016 - 2020)

- Managed development lifecycle of data pipelines and web/map applications, delivering tools for hundreds of internal and thousands of external users. (Python, Flask, JavaScript, ArcGIS ecosystem)
- Spearheaded migrating Southeastern US natural-gas GIS production dataset between wildly different models via custom Extract-Transform-Load application. (Python, Flask, ESRI, JavaScript, SQLAlchemy, Utility Network)
- Served as team leader for a department of 8 software engineers.

Lead Developer - US Patriot Tactical (2011 - 2016)

- Developed in-house ERP system in Ruby-on-Rails for warehouse management and order processing (\$3M/mo. average).
- Created ReST-based product service with Sinatra, Ruby and JavaScript to provide real-time product data to 3rd party storefronts via AJAX calls.

Education

- BS Geographic Information Systems (2010)
- AS General Studies, Biology (2008)